Steve Niles

I'm a full stack developer (front & back-end, desktop, library) using object-oriented and functional programming styles primarily in .NET. I'm most experienced with languages C# and Javascript, frameworks AngularJS and React, and using parallel and asynchronous programming styles.

Experience

Software Developer - Yangaroo c#, javascript, reactjs, sql-server

May 2019 → Current

Senior Developer - MRI Software

Aug 2013 → May 2019

c#, javascript, typescript, angularjs, sql-server

- Architect & implement features for general & client-specific web-based enterprise systems
- Design & build in-house tools to improve development workflows & processes
- Set up & maintain virtualized development and testing environments

Part-time Object Oriented Programming Teacher - Niagara College c#, .net, visual-studio-2010

Jan 2013 → Apr 2013

- Instructed students in the use of Visual Studio and .NET using C#
- · Taught object oriented programming techniques
- Guided and assessed student performance

Computer Programming Research Assistant – Niagara Research

Sep 2007 → Apr 2013

- c#, php, javascript, kml, postgresql
 - · Projects included creating AutoCAD extensions and real-time remote sensing visualization systems
 - · Trained junior developers in programming and image processing techniques

• Worked on research and development projects in partnership with local businesses

Education

BSc (Honours) in Computer Science - Brock University

 $2009 \rightarrow 2013$

Courses of interest included:

- · Artificial intelligence
- · Algorithm analysis
- · Compiler construction

Computer Programmer / Analyst Diploma - Niagara College

2006 → 2009

- Three year program
- · Co-op with college's research department
- President's Honour Roll every semester

Projects & Interests

Jargon.Guard - https://github.com/steveniles/Jargon.Guard

Dec 2018 → Current

A set of simple guard clauses for method parameters

The .NET Compiler Platform - https://github.com/dotnet/roslyn/pull/8195 c# visual-studio

Jan 2016 → Apr 2016

Found and fixed a bug in the static analysis code of Microsoft's .NET Compiler Platform ("Roslyn")

MandelZoom - https://github.com/steveniles/MandelZoom c#, gdi, gdi+, mandelbrot

Dec 2012 → Aug 2014

A fractal screen saver & small wiki guide on various issues relating to screen saver creation and fractal image processing